br@brendanrodgers.uk
"filinkedin.com/in/rodgersbrendan
",¬brendanrodgers.uk/portfolio
Brendan Rodgers
Digital Content Strategist
"London
",•
+447913566551

Digital content strategist with over 10+ years who loves working with technology, SaaS and commerce brands. Experience leading projects and teams, including with global enterprise clients. Specialised in delivering AAA quality content and marketing strategies that create and grow customer and prospect experiences for B2B audiences through owned channels and paid media. Background in tech, non prots, events and design, allowing for a deep understanding of customer experience optimisation.

I specialise in connecting the dots between complex problems to create briefs to create storytelling narratives that set creative teams up for success and allow products to resonate with their markets. I am experienced in building strong relationships through workshops, partnerships and collaborations with key clients and contributors to form high-performing teams that achieve success.

-

ï€ f

- Dentsu is the fth largest advertising agency in the world, and I sat within Merkle B2B, the subsidiary that focuses on ABX, Media and Creative for leading international businesses. During which I developed a working knowledge of sustainability challenges for Enterprise. I built briefs, provided strategic direction for client projects and hosted workshops and client presentations. I also assisted on pitches and wider content strategy processes for the agency. Projects and clients include:

Shell - Decarbonising your value chain [Link]

Adobe - Creative Cloud for Teams (dynamic content)

Adobe - Acrobat's Got It - Sustainability

Adobe - Acrobat Sign Customer Stories

Intel - ABX Content Strategy

I provided consulting services on Marketing & Content Strategy, Digital Fundraising Strategy, and Customer experience.

Projects and clients include:

Everywhere +

virtual webinar platform for charities

Content Strategy & Experience audit for Everywhere+ website (review ongoing)

Also provided: Journey and UX guidance & tech recommendations

Global technology company based in sydney - key product is an advanced fundraising cms platform.

Lead global digital marketing campaigns across multiple online channels to promote Funraisin's tech platform,

brand and thought leadership. Activities included global online events, building relations with sector press, 1st party digital, and partner relationship management.

Led partnership projects, managed teams of 4-8 people, responsible for oversight and strategy, task delegation and deliverables.

Led a COVID support initiative at the start of the pandemic that oered free fundraising platforms to non-

prots -this boosted our number of monthly SQLs by 70% for 3-4 months. 30% of which, becameDec 2022Present Senior Content Strategist DentsuAegis (Merkle B2B)

JUL 22Dec 22 DIGITAL & CONTENT CONSULTANT (contract)

Brendan Rodgers Consulting

MAR 2020JUL 2022 DIGITAL DIRECTOR (EMEA, APAC, NA)

Funraisin LtdSummary

Work experience -

-

- longstanding customers post-promotion.

Delivered over 20 events from 2020-22, including virtual, metaverse and in-person. Peak registrations totalled 350 simultaneous attendees. Managed over 30 sector relationships, and generated a brand halo eect for thought leadership and expertise.

Oversaw multiple international product GTM launches across EMEA, NA and APAC including each of which were multi-channel campaigns requiring cross-functional input from sales, customer success, creative and product teams.

Achieved huge audience growth (60%) year on year, twice '20-'21 and '21-'22. Slashing costs by generating 5x ROI, and content engagement scores of 60% - inspiring other departments to follow.

Delivered accurate attribution modelling for ROI planning. Achieved this by building out internal data processes. Focused and evolved sophistication over time, utilising UTMs, Segments, analytics, and dashboards, to scale with the business.

Led the customer loyalty campaign that sent medals to over 600 high-value customers worldwide. Drove 300% boost in social activity during customer loyalty campaign. Oversaw budget, production and delivery of the physical and virtual experience. The virtual aspect is still used annually as a lead generation tool. Redeveloped onboarding journey for new customers driving feature adoption, training, as a result, supporting customer success & retention eorts.

31

SaaS Technology start-up with B-Corp status that provides a Social Media Management Product and Agency service. Cross-functional growth strategist and planner, and responsible for team formation, task delegation, project planning and delivery. Goals included driving registration to the Social Platform tool, but also driving adoption and engagement with the product itself by using all data available to me including engagement, activation, and churn metrics.

Increased product activation rate from 38% to 68% by building brand strategy into customer experience ows. Utilised analytics and heat maps to reduce user frustrations leading collaborations with tech, customer success and design departments

Audience voice & GTM rep for the Product Steering Group. Achieved buy-in for key product features including in-app analytics, personalised best-time-to-post data, and hashtag suggestion tool. Achieved a 280% increase in trac to the key sales page. Prior to this, I had reworked the key sales page to achieve a 73.91% activation rate, outperforming the original page by 15%.

Attained a CPA of £7 and CTR 1.7% for white-paper acquisition multi-channel campaign including paid and organic. Led tech and design teams to build custom CTA blocks for website and product increased avg conversion by 25%.

I provide consulting services on Marketing, Technology, Digital Fundraising and Event best practices. NERVE TUMOURS UK

nonprot seeking to support those with nerve-tumour conditions

Built CRM strategy for engaging Livery companies & Rotaries, created 300% ROI in two months (including multi-year agreements) & delivered 500 new donor contacts

PROMOTING ECONOMIC PLURALISM

nonprot promoting diverse economic values

Audience analysis & content audit

Digital agency for household brands including the disability charity Scope.

Wrote nomination to BIMA Awards, won Best Website Partnership

CRM implementation & analytics tracking

Website & Email marketingSEP 2019FEB 2020 DIGITAL DEMAND GENERATION LEAD Lightful

JUL 2019SEPT 2019 DIGITAL CONTENT CONSULTANT (contract)

Brendan Rodgers Consulting

JAN 2019JUL 2019 DIGITAL CONTENT MARKETING MANAGER

Aqueduct Advertising & Design -

- Content Marketing strategy; Event 6-month strategy, budgeting and delivery

SEO, Social, Email and Web

High-value email campaigns

Charity for people suering from Nerve tumour-related conditions (i.e. neurobromatosis)

Fully transformed the national brand and led the implementation of change process from The Neuro

Foundation to Nerve Tumours UK.

Sat on Extraordinary Brand Committee with CEO & Board of Trustees, and owned process end to end from agency procurement to brand applications and merchandising.

Led team of three sta, and owned multiple hiring processes.

Conceived and delivered agship crowdfunding campaign raising £70,000+ "#OneMoreNurse"

Conceived and delivered bespoke student fun-run Challenge Event "Runderpants" raising £35k

Managed multiple agencies, technology partners and commercial relationships

Led end-to-end digital transformation of charity.

Donation tools, new Fundraising Hub custom peer-to-peer area of the website

Launched e-commerce shop

Launched Email marketing newsletters

Microsite for children's services

Interactive chat functions with moderation tools

CMS upgrades & Introduced CRM database

COMMUNICATIONS & SERVICES COORDINATOR AUG 2015 - JAN 2016

Supporter-mobilising nationwide awareness day campaigns (yearly) driving 300% engagement YoY consistently

3 patient information day events per year in collaboration with hospitals and medical experts

Digitisation of membership records by hiring temporary sta (completed in 3 months) and overseeing the modernisation of membership recruitment processes.

Apprenticeship framework charity to print/manufacturing industries.

Delivering comprehensive digital branding school engagement initiatives including printed workbooks, social content, photography and event support.

Animations for agship apprenticeship campaign. Materials are used in multiple international forums worldwide,

US, Vietnam, Hong Kong.

Programmatic content publisher

Created integrated ad units that fused interactive graphics to react to in-video content, creating a rich ad experience for consumer brands.

CLIENT PROJECTS:

Netix

Motor Neurone Disease, awareness movie

Captain Phillips, Tom Hanks Movie This is the End, Seth Rogan Movie

Blizzard Activision

Travelex

BNY Melon

Smashbox

London Rimmel

Ann SummersAUG 2015JAN 2019 HEAD OF MARKETING & OPERATIONS

Nerve Tumours UK (formerly The Neuro Foundation)

OCT 2014AUG 2015 DIGITAL DESIGNER (contract)

Proskills Global (formerly Proskills UK)

FEB 2013JAN 2014 TECHNICAL IMPLEMENTATION MANAGER

Scoota (formerly Rockabox media ltd) -

A small digital production business I started supporting SMEs and local political campaigns.

Consulted and delivered digital marketing and communications strategies for a wide variety of clients including London-based SMEs and political campaigns. Developed marketing strategies to meet the client's brief resulting in

the successful delivery of a variety of campaigns.

Key achievements:

Social media and video campaign for a London-based nancial SME resulting in an increased digital presence increasing their web trac and social media followers.

Internal selection political campaign for a prospective parliamentary candidate. Delivery of videos, website and social media with coherent political messaging and branding throughout. This resulted in the candidate winning

their campaign to compete at the 2015 national election.AUG 2012FEB 2013 FOUNDER & COMMUNICATIONS CONSULTANT

Ambr Media

CMS: WordPress, Wix, ExpressionEngine, Squarespace

CRM: Hubspot, Salesforce, Act365,

Fundraising: Funraisin, Raisely, Justgiving, Givepanel (EverydayHero, Virgin Money Giving)

Marketing: Active Campaign, Campaign Monitor, Autopilot / Ortto, Mailchimp, ConstantContact, OptIn Monster,

LeadPages, Facebook Business, Linkedin Ads, Google Ads, Instagram Business, Lightful, Sprout Social, ContentCal,

Hootsuite, Buer, Falcon.io

Analytics: SEMRush, Fifty.io, Google Analytics, Tag Manager, Keyword Planner, Segment, HotJar, Mixpanel

Project: JIRA, Conuence, Trello, Monday.com, Asana, Notion

Design: Photoshop, Illustrator, After Eects, Premiere Pro, Canva Pro, Concepts,

Oce: Google Workspace Docs: Sheets, Slides, MS Oce: Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Apple iWork: Pages, Numbers,

Keynote

Agile: It's Not Just for Software Linkedin Learning (2022)

Growth Marketing for Founders

Dan Martell (2019)

Introduction to Fundraising

Certicate

Chartered Institute of Fundraising (2017)

Media Communications & Culture and Philosophy (Dual Honours)

Bachelor of Arts Degree

Keele University, UK (2008 - 2011)

Film & Culture in a Korean Context

Diploma (Student Exchange)

Donggukk University, Seoul (2010)

Training for London Landmarks Half Marathon 2023

'Dog dad' to Luna the Labradoodle

Seeing friends and family

Live music, theatre, reading, old school video games.

Technology, practical applications for the betterment of the planet/society Software

Education / Training

Interests